<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>CraftyOS Blog</title><link>https://craftydh.github.io/CraftyOS-Blog/</link><description>Recent content on CraftyOS Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://craftydh.github.io/CraftyOS-Blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interrupts - Timers and Keyboard</title><link>https://craftydh.github.io/CraftyOS-Blog/posts/interrupts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://craftydh.github.io/CraftyOS-Blog/posts/interrupts/</guid><description>Interrupts Interrupts are essential to a computer functioning, they allow your keyboard and mouse to interrupt the CPU and tell it that an event is waiting. This means that when a program is running the kernel gets control of the CPU so that it can process the keyboard event. This also enables the CPU to tell us when we do something stupid such as dividing 0 by 0.
Exceptions To handle exceptions we must first program the IDT and GDT, checkout Phillip&amp;rsquo;s tutorial for more on those.</description></item><item><title>Take 2, a fresh start...</title><link>https://craftydh.github.io/CraftyOS-Blog/posts/restart/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://craftydh.github.io/CraftyOS-Blog/posts/restart/</guid><description>Why must I restart? Well quite simply UEFI is a pain. But seriously I spend 72 hours rewriting and rewriting my interrupt handlers to no avail. I believe that the problem was that I could not setup paging correctly and as such caused general protection faults and as I could not handle these faults I wasted so much time. Therefore in order to catch up to my schedule I have chosen to follow Philipp Oppermann&amp;rsquo;s blog_os to completion and then implement the other features on top.</description></item><item><title>The beginnings of CraftyOS</title><link>https://craftydh.github.io/CraftyOS-Blog/posts/start/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://craftydh.github.io/CraftyOS-Blog/posts/start/</guid><description>Why make an OS? The purpose of this project is to learn how computers work at a basic level by programming a bare bones OS. This will help myself learn the various complexities behind the OS abstractions that are used in conventional programs.
Additionally as this project is for a school project, I had the requirement of creating a digitial application in 16 weeks. With that in mind, I wanted to choose a complex topic where I could make something cool while learning another area of computer science.</description></item></channel></rss>